Scripting conventions and syntax.
スクリプト コーディングルールおよび文法。
Coding syntax simply means the structure
コーディングの文法は言語の構造を意味しますが、
of the language, and some conventions are
いくつかのコーディングルールは
essential to learning to read and write code.
コードの読み書きを学ぶうえで重要です。
For example the dot operator.
例えばドット演算子をみてみます。
The dot operator is a full stop, or period,
ドット演算子はコードにおける用語の間の
seen between words within code.
完全な区切り、またはピリオドです。
It works like writing the line of an address.
住所の行を書くよう働きをします。
For example consider this line of code.
例えば次のようなコードを考えて見ます。
Here we could consider Debug the country
ここでは Debug が国の名前で、
and Log the city. We're drilling down in to
Log が都市の名前です。ここでは Debug の中にあるものに
things that are within Debug,
ドリルダウンしていて、
Log being one of those elements.
Log はそのような要素のひとつです。
Then for example in this part of the code
例えばコードのこの部分においては
transform is the country, position is the city
transform は国の名前であり、position は 都市の名前で、
and X is the street we're trying to locate.
X は 探そうとしている番地のようなものです。
So the dot operator is effectively
ドット演算子は要するに
allowing you to separate or access
Unity の複合的なアイテムの要素を
elements of a compound item in Unity.
分割したりアクセスできるようにしています。
A compound item being something that
複合的なアイテムは多くの要素を含む
contains many elements.
ものです。
So for example transform contains
例えば Transform には
position, rotation and scale.
Position, Rotation および Scale が含まれます。
So the dot operator is used to choose position,
このためドット演算子は Position の選択に使用され、
and then position contains X, Y or Z.
Position には X, Y, Z が含まれます。
So we've then chosen X by using the dot
ここではドット演算子を再び使用することで
operator once again. The next piece of syntax
X を選択しています。次の文法は
is the semicolon. The semicolon is used
セミコロンです。セミコロンは
to terminate statements, which is why
ステートメントを終了するのに使用され、
you'll always see it at the end.
このために必ず行末にあります。
However not all parts of the code are statements.
しかしコードの全てがステートメントであるとはかぎりません。
For example the opening and closing of a
例えばクラス宣言の
class declaration, or the opening
開始や終了、
and closing of functions or if statements.
関数や if 文の開始や終了などです。
Anything using a curly brace does
{} を使用するものはすべて
not need a semicolon at the end of it.
その最後にセミコロンが必要ありません。
Any statements within these, i.e., after
これらの中にあるステートメントは全て
the opening or before the closing
すなわち開始または終了の前は
will end with a semicolon.
セミコロンで終わります。
Indenting.
次はインデントです。
Indenting is an important part of writing
インデントはコードを書く上で重要なことです。
code that's both presentable and legible.
これによりコードの見映えをあげて読みやすくします。
Indenting code is not technically necessary
技術的にはインデントは不要なのですが、
but it allows you to read it more easily
これによりコードは読みやすくなり
as it's used to show the functional structure
これによりコード全体の機能構造が
of your code.
分かりやすくなります。
The code you see here is already fully indented.
ここで見るコードはすでに完全にインデントされています。
But if I outdent all of this code
しかし、もしこのコード全てを同時に
using Shift and Tab
Shift + Tab でアウトデントした場合、
we can do it a step at a time.
ひとつひとつのステップを見ていくことが出来ます。
So to begin with my public class statement
それでは初めに public クラス宣言
declaration starts here
はここで始まり
and ends at the bottom, so I know that
下で終わるので、
everything within it needs indenting
その中のものは少なくとも 1 回インデントが必要である
by at least 1.
ことが分かります。
I'm using the Tab key to do this.
Tab キーを使用して行います。
Next, in my Start function, which starts
次に、 Start 関数は
here on line 7 and ends on line 14,
この 7 行目で始まり、 14 行目で終わります。
I have a few lines of code.
コードが数行あり、
So they all need indenting because they're
これらはすべて Start 関数の中にあるため
within the Start function.
インデントが必要です。
Then finally within my if statement.
最後に、 if 文の中には
I have a debug log line of code,
Debug.log の行のコードがあるため、
which I'm going to indent as well.
これもインデントします。
So I can visually trace a line going
これにより視覚的に行をトレースすることが出来て、
down the page and spot where all
ページの下へ行って、
my code blocks start and end,
コードブロックが開始および終了する箇所を見つけられます。
simply because I've used indentation.
これはインデントを行ってあるためです。
Generally speaking MonoDevelop should help you
一般的にいうと MonoDevelop により
with this and do it automatically
これを行うことがより容易になり、自動的に行われますが
but just in case you've got anything wrong
もし何か間違っている場合
or you've pressed Tab in the wrong place
あるいは間違った箇所で Tab を押した場合
you should make sure that all of your
すべてのインデントが意味あるように
indentation makes sense, especially
注意をすべきであり、
if you're working with someone else on your code.
特にコードを共同作業で他人に共有していると重要です。
Finally, Comments.
最後に、コメントです。
Comments can be used literally as
コメントは言葉どおりであり
they sound to comment about a piece of code
コードに一部に関して
in order to leave yourself a note.
何かメモを残すようにしてコメントを入れます。
You can write a single line comment by
一行のコメントを書くには
using a double forward slash.
// を使用します。
Or you can write a multiple line comment
または複数行のコメントを書くには
by starting with a forward slash,
/* で
an asterisk and terminating with the
開始して
opposite, an asterisk followed by a forward slash.
/* で終了します。
And you can continue to write as many
さらにコメントは好きな行数だけ
lines as you want. So comments can be used
書くことが出来ます。コメントは
to leave yourself or other coders a note.
自身から他のプログラマにメモを残すために使用します。
But it can also be used to disable parts
もう一つの使用方法は
of code temporarily.
コードを一時的に無効化する場合です。
So for example if I want to disable
例えばもしこの if 文を
this if statement I can put in a
無効化したい場合は
multi-line comment starting before it
/* を最初に入れて
and terminating after it.
最後に */ で閉じます。
You can see that my code editor MonoDevelop
MonoDevelop のエディタにより
is there to help me see that this part
により、どの部分が無効になったか
is disabled. It changes the syntax
明示してくれます。
colouring of this part of code
その部分のコードの色が
showing me that it's not actually
実行される部分でないことを
being executed. So this will not be
明示します。このため、この箇所は
executed until I remove the comment again.
再びコメント記号を消すまで実行されることはありません。
The compiler, or Unity in this sense,
要するにコンパイラは（つまり Unity 自体が）、
effectively just ignores what's going
そのコメントの中にある
on within that comment.
部分を無視します。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)